An anti-hate satire.
Jojo Rabbit is a comedy, war, drama film directed by Taika Waititi.
Jojo, a lonely German boy during World War II has his world shaken when he
learns that his single mother is hiding a Jewish girl in their home.
Influenced by a buffoonish imaginary version of Adolf Hitler, he begins to question his
beliefs and confront the conflict between propaganda and his own humanity.
Jojo, played by Roman Griffin Davis.
Elsa, played by Thomasin McKenzie.
Rosie, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Adolf, played by Taika Waititi.
Captain Klenzendorf, played by Sam Rockwell.
Fraulein Rahm, played by Rebel Wilson.
Jojo Rabbit is a 2019 satirical black comedy-drama film written and directed by
Taika Waititi, adapted from Christine Leunens' 2008 book Caging Skies.
Roman Griffin Davis makes his film debut as the title character, Johannes "Jojo" Betzler, a ten-year-old Hitler Youth member
who finds out that his mother (Scarlett Johansson) is hiding a Jewish girl (Thomasin McKenzie) in their attic.
He must then question his beliefs while dealing with the intervention of his imaginary friend, a childlike,
eccentric version of Adolf Hitler (played by Waititi) with a comedic stance on the politics of the war.
The film also stars Sam Rockwell, Rebel Wilson,
Stephen Merchant, and Alfie Allen.
Waititi wrote the screenplay in 2011, a year after his
mother described the premise of Caging Skies.
He rewrote the first draft, which as a rough adaptation of the dark-toned source material did not contain
much comedy; it was also in the rewritten version that Adolf's character was included.
Waititi recalled the pitching process as exhausting.
In 2012, it landed on the Black List, where it remained in a development limbo until
several years later when Fox Searchlight Pictures showed interest in it.
A tight casting schedule started with principal photography in the
Czech Republic in May 2018, finishing two months later.
Post-production included adding the visual effects, editing done by Tom
Eagles, as well as a score composed by Michael Giacchino.
Jojo Rabbit had its world premiere at the 44th Toronto International Film Festival on
September 8, 2019, where it won the Grolsch People's Choice Award.
It was later released theatrically in the United States on October 18.
The film received positive reviews, though critics were divided on
its comedic treatment of the subject of Nazism.
It was chosen by the National Board of Review and the American Film
Institute as one of the ten best films of the year.
Among its numerous accolades, the film won the Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay, while also
being nominated for five other awards, including Best Picture, at the 92nd Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, world war
ii, jew persecution, satire, imaginary friend.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.